Teodor Fratiloiu

Recent EE MS graduate from TUM

teodor.fratiloiu@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/teodor-fratiloiu +44 20 3239 8947

June 6, 2023

- My CV is on the next page -

Dear hiring team,

Please allow me to introduce myself. My name is Teo, and I'm a recent graduate from the Technical University of Munich, holding both BS and MS degrees in Electrical and Computer Engineering.

I like to think of myself as being versatile in the workplace, both as a problem-solver and engineer, as well as in the relationships I build with people across the organization. In my previous cybersecurity role at Celonis, which was in a hyper-growth environment (5x in my team alone during my time there), I was often given just a list of goals and a few new contacts to work with (sometimes several timezones away). This helped me find comfort when navigating uncertain scenarios, and allowed me to learn how to construct productive and value- driven working relationships across corporate hierarchies and cultures, respectively. I worked on BC/DR projects, internal audits, and the successful implementation of an ISMS, as well as multiple passed SOC 2 external audits. I was also involved with internal training and phishing training, as well as early-stage incident response. Given my technical background, I'd like to transition into an information security engineering position for the next step of my career, which is why this opportunity feels very appealing to me. I can discuss about this at length during a phone call. Finally, effective, intercultural and professional communication was also required in my role as a student assistant at the TUM, where I helped the teaching staff break down complex engineering and IT issues to highly diverse groups of students.

My work experience is complemented by my education at the TUM, where I specialized in machine learning and C/C++ programming on the one hand, and cybersecurity on the other hand. Although it's densely packed, I attempted to paint an accurate picture of my technical background in my resume, including both my technical projects from throughout university, as well as my work experience at my previous employer. I have the right to work in the UK via the HPI route and will not require sponsorship at this time.

All in all, I'd like to further my career in a place where complex, technical, cross-departmental projects are brought to life. Canva's culture seems amazing, and this position could definitely help me further develop my security career, which is why I am incredibly excited about this opportunity.

Sincerely yours,

Teodor Fratiloiu

Teodor Fratiloiu

teodor.fratiloiu@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/teodor-fratiloiu

UK HPI Visa Holder (with right to work), EU Citizen

Profile

Recent graduate of the Technical University of Munich with an MS degree in computer engineering. Specialized in cybersecurity, machine learning and high-performance software development. During my studies, I gained **2 years** of work **experience** in a hyper-growth environment (5x team-level, 3x company growth) at Celonis, Germany's and New York's highest-valued startup.

Education

Technical University of Munich (TUM) -

M.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology (2020-2023)

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology (2017-2020)

Work Experience

JUNIOR INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST, CELONIS; MUNICH (GERMANY) – DEC 2020 - FEB 2023

- Developed automations to collect over 50 types of evidence for continuous compliance with ISO 27001 and SOC 2, identified and harmonized audit control gaps across various frameworks
- Helped author and test BC/DR plans for EMEA and NA entities, conferred with stakeholders to account for critical data assets in 2 enterprise SaaS products hosted in a multi-cloud environment
- Worked in AWS, Azure and GCP environments
- Periodically reviewed the access rights to cloud systems with up to 6-digit user counts; crossqueried databases to ensure appropriateness
- Assisted with writing security policies, SOPs, and training material, managed automated phishing training for the entire organization

INFOSEC LECTURE STUDENT ASSISTANT, TUM - 2020

Prepared lab content for students, explained solutions and hosted educational videos. Assisted the rest of the teaching staff during live remote classes for students in Munich and Singapore.

MEMBER AND MENTOR, ADVEISOR (TUM) - 2018 - 2019

Participated in a 1-year soft-skills and personal development program with professional coaching, including several 3-5 day offsite seminars in the Bavarian Alps. Applied the acquired knowledge by hosting over 10 project management and business communication workshops during my second year of university for "mentee" freshmen, which helped me find and perfect my own leadership style.

Skills

Security - ISO 27001, SOC 2, NIST, OWASP

Cloud - AWS, Azure, GCP audit and deployment

Programming - C, C++11 and up, Python, JS/TS, TensorFlow/Keras, Docker & cloud, Git, UNIX

Technical Project Experience

Here, I would like to further explain my deeply technical background, which complements my work experience in cybersecurity.

MASTER'S THESIS - PEEKING INTO THE DECISION-MAKING PROCESS IN THE HUMAN MIND VIA DEEP LEARNING MODELS

- Collected and engineered labelled training data to represent >12,000 trading decisions, architected and trained deep learning models to emulate human decision-making (Keras, JAX)
- Assessed my own DL models against behavioral economics research results

DISTRIBUTED. HIGH PERFORMANCE COMPUTING - LAB

- Solved a very large asynchronous value iteration problem in C++17 and ensured thread security
- Used multiprocessing (OpenMP), MPI, CFFI, and created my own build systems in CMake

FULLY REMOTE API-BASED IOT PROGRAMMING - LAB

 Wrote type-secure TypeScript routines for a remote IoT "factory" with sensors and servo robot and securely deployed said scripts over the public Internet with real-time monitoring

FUTURE ELECTRICITY PRICE PREDICTION - TEAM PROJECT

 Implemented a time-series prediction algorithm with reinforcement learning, developed our own type-secure full-stack app to visualize the results

BACHELOR'S THESIS - TINYFACE: EXTREME EDGE FACE DETECTION ON EMBEDDED DEVICES

 Trained, then compressed a neural network to function on low-power embedded hardware via pruning, graph analysis and quantization as part of a new research project (PhD level); returned to embedded ML during my master's by reengaging with the same group

ASTEROIDS ON AN STM32 MOBILE CONSOLE - LAB

- Close to metal implementation of the Atari classic in C on microcontrollers with color displays and joysticks, with cross-device multiplayer; enforced real-time computing
- Implemented task scheduling via an RTOS, wrote embedded build systems and toolchains